Zachary D. Schmidt

(651) 398-4727 • schmidtz123@gmail.com • zschmidt.github.io • Eugene, OR

Personal Statement

I'm interested in solving interesting and novel problems using cutting edge technologies. Professionally, I've been most closely involved in web development, where I've spent several years working as a full stack developer in a Javascript/C#stack, and previously using a more diverse stack involving Action Script, ColdFusion, and Java. I have also worked in a role where I wrote software for a scientific instrument running an embedded Windows operating system. I have been exposed to and involved with the technology decisions for everything from front end Javascript frameworks to the implementation of microservices deployed in Azure utilizing emerging technologies, and I'm always excited to learn about more in order to broaden my technological horizons.

Technical Skills

Languages: C#.NET Core, C++, HTML5/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, MS SQL/MySQL, AS3, AngularJS,

Angular 2+, ColdFusion, YAML, LightStreamer, Java **Packages:** Helm, Tiller, Kubernetes, Docker, Git, Mercurial

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Visual Studio 2012, SQL Server Management Studio 2012, and supporting tools

including Notepad++, Sublime, Atom, Tortoise SVN, Paint.NET, and PuTTY

Databases: Cosmos, Microsoft SQL, MySQL

Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, MacOS, Fedora, Debian, Arch

Methodologies: Agile, Kanban, Waterfall

Education

• University of Oregon

M.S. Computer Science

• Minnesota State University, Mankato

B.S. Computer Science

B.S. Mathematics

Eugene, OR

2015 - 2017

26 1 262

Mankato, MN

2008 - 2013

Experience

• Qualtrics

Remote
November 2020 - December 2020

Software Contractor

- Two month contract focusing on updating an AngularJS website to provide keyboard accessibility including the addition of focus styles, an updated DOM order, and programmatically handled keyboard actions

Technical Environment: HTML/CSS, TypeScript, AngularJS

• ATP Development

Remote

Lead Software Engineer

June 2018 - June 2020

- Worked as a full stack engineer to create a TypeScript/Angular client with a C#.NET Core backend, utilizing Cosmos DB and real-time communication via SignalR
- Oversaw deployment of application on Microsoft's Azure cloud platform
- Configured CI/CD pipelines which ended on Docker instances managed by a Kubernetes cluster
- Maintained resources on Kubernetes via Helm and Tiller
- Dealt with MX and CNAME records for our domain, and wrote an automated email service using SendGrid

Technical Environment: Cosmos, Helm, Tiller, Kubernetes, Docker, HTML/CSS, TypeScript, Angular 2+, C#.NET Core

• Thermo Fisher Scientific

Eugene, OR

Software Engineering Contractor

January 2018 - June 2018

- Wrote software for a flow cytometer using C++with an MFC library
- Participated in Kanban in order to maintain an Agile workflow

Technical Environment: C++

• University of Oregon

Eugene, OR

Graduate Teaching Fellow

September 2015 - December 2017

 Taught lab sessions and held office hours for Intro to Web Programming, Web Applications II, Computer Science III, Computer Organization, and Intro to Game Programming

• ImageTrend, Inc.

Lakeville, MN

Software Developer

January 2014 - September 2015

- Web development using a variety of interconnected technologies such as ColdFusion for a CMS, AngularJS/Bootstrap for responsive application, and C#.NET for RESTful APIs
- Led the development and deployment of a real-time auction platform using Lightstreamer with a Java back-end which is capable of supporting ten thousand users
- Used Amazon's EC2 to host PowerShell scripted bots which were programmatically used to load test our applications

Technical Environment: C#.NET, AngularJS, Javascript, HTML/CSS, Lightstreamer, AS3, ColdFusion, Microsoft SQL, Java

Honors

- Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America
- Curt Stangler/Accenture Scholarship, Fall 2013
- Best GTF: 2015-2016, 2016-2017 Academic Year(s)